(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
FUWAWA MOCOCO
OOZORA SUBARU
AZKi
MURASAKI SHION
YUKIHANA LAMY
MOMOSUZU NENE
NAKIRI AYAME
HOUSHOU MARINE
SHIRAKAMI FUBUKI
SAKURA MIKO
Re:member colors
SAKURA MIKO BIRTHDAY LIVE 2025
夢ってなんだろう
What is a dream?
上手く言えないわたしへ
To the me who can't say it well
歌っていいんだよ
It's okay to sing
眩しい光の中で
Inside the dazzling light
恥ずかしくて
Being embarrassed
flower rhapsody
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
編曲：神田ジョン from PENGUIN RESEARCH
flower rhapsody
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Shota Horie
Arrangement: John Kanda from PENGUIN RESEARCH
悔しがりなわたしへ
To the frustrated me
泣いていいんだよ
It's okay to cry
ちゃんと伝えたいなら
If you want to convey it properly
孤独は消えないよ
Loneliness won't disappear
肩を寄せ合うんだよ
We'll lean on each other
さみしいよ　いとしいよ
I'm lonely, I'm dear,
大丈夫
it's okay.
それがわたしのストーリー
That is my story.
風に迷い笑うひとひら
A single petal wandering and smiling in the wind.
秋が芽吹いた分だけ
Just as much as autumn has sprouted,
繋ぎ合える手のひら
our palms can connect.
それは色とりどり
It's so colorful,
目まぐるしくて綺麗で
dizzying and beautiful.
夢みたいだねってさ
You said it's like a dream,
きっと君が望むでしょう
surely that's what you wish for.
みんな！みこの生誕祭ライブ
Everyone! Welcome to Miko's
2025、来てくれてありがとう！
Birthday Live 2025! Thanks for coming!
盛り上がっていくぞ！
Let's get fired up!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅん♡
Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun Kyun ♡
ねぇねぇあのねこれガチ
Hey hey, listen, this is for real,
みんな友達目に居るカタチてっか言ってマジ
everyone's a friend, in my eyes, like seriously.
それはすなわちみこしゅて話
In other words, it's Miko's story,
いろんな私超見て欲しい
I want you to see all of me.
エリートあいさつ！みんなにゃっはろー！
Elite greeting! Nyahello everyone!
エリートスマイル！えへへきゅん！
Elite smile! Ehehe, kyun!
エリートダンス！みーみーみこみこ！
Elite dance! Mi-mi-miko-miko!
エリートイングリッシュ！I'll be back!
Elite English! I'll be back!
まあね、時にはね、落ち込んじゃうこともあるよ。
Well, you know, sometimes I do get depressed.
そんな時ははなまるあげるね！
In those times, I'll give you a gold star!
おまえらよく聞けー！
Listen up, you guys!
みこのメドレー、いっくぞー！
Miko's medley, let's go!
はにゃってあにゃってほにゃっと混ぜたらキュンしちゃうからミコチュン
Hanya, anya, honya, mix them up and you'll go 'kyun,' Miko-kyun!
ぽにゃってぽにってぽよった最強うにゃうにゃしよう一緒に
Ponya, poni, poyotta, the best! Let's go 'unya-unya' together!
せーの！
One, two!
ドキドキめめめきゅん！
Doki doki meme-me kyun!
ぴょこぴょこめめめきゅん？
Pyoko pyoko meme-me kyun?
キラキラめめめきゅん！
Kira kira meme-me kyun!
きゅんきゅん！
Kyun kyun!
君にきゅんをあげるよ！
I'll give you a kyun!
What time is it now? 1135!
Say in Japanese! 1135!
あーひとりでいると考え込んじゃうな
Ah, when I'm alone, I start overthinking.
自信と不安でサンドイッチ
Sandwiched between confidence and anxiety.
わかんなくなってきちゃった
I've stopped understanding everything.
みこかわいい？
Is Miko cute?
間違ってないのだ！君がいる！
I'm not wrong! Because you're here!
みこちはエリート、だよねぇ。
Miko-chi is an elite, right?
黙れ！みこちは恥ずかしいよ！
Shut up! Miko-chi is embarrassed!
言うて好きなクセに
Even though you say that, you like it.
毎分毎秒ドッジボール、あっちいね楽しいね
Every minute, every second, like dodgeball. It's heated and fun, isn't it?
本気で想い合って
Thinking of each other seriously,
そのくせバカばっか言い合って好き勝手やってんね
despite always bickering like idiots and doing as we please.
でも今日くらいはちゃんと聞いててね？
But at least today, listen properly, okay?
控えめに言って神、伝えたい愛、朝も夜も胸いっぱいさ
To put it mildly, you're a god. The love I want to share fills my heart day and night.
クラクラしちゃってたまんないの、純度100%で大好きだ！
I'm so dizzy, I can't take it. I love you with 100% purity!
ギュッてチャーミング、全世界共通
A charming hug, universal across the world.
ギュッてチャーミング、ラブアンドピース
A charming hug, love and peace.
きっとお似合いだよ You & Me、このまま二人で･･･
We're surely a good match, You & Me. Just the two of us like this...
なんちってー！
Just kidding!
君にも届けたい、他にはないアミューズメント
I want to bring you a unique kind of amusement.
「いいみこ」って届けて毎日
Send me a 'Good Miko' every single day.
目を合わせたら笑ってくれる、当たり前のような奇跡
You smile when our eyes meet. A miracle that seems so ordinary.
もらってばかりじゃいらんない、今ここで恩返し
I can't just keep taking. I'll pay you back right here and now.
ずっと見ててよね？
Keep watching me, okay?
控えめに言って神、伝えたい愛、朝も夜も胸いっぱいさ
To put it mildly, you're a god. The love I want to share fills my heart day and night.
クラクラしちゃってたまんないの、純度100%で大好きだ！
I'm so dizzy, I can't take it. I love you with 100% purity!
ギュッてチャーミング、全世界共通
A charming hug, universal across the world.
ギュッてチャーミング、ラブアンドピース
A charming hug, love and peace.
きっとお似合いだよ You & Me
We're surely a good match, You & Me.
飽きるほどいっぱい隣で歌うよ、このまま二人で･･･
I'll sing by your side until you've had enough. Just the two of us...
なんちってー！
Just kidding!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nyahello World!!!
...にゃっほろーわーるど!
...Nya-hello World!
最高! エリート巫女に仕上げてあげる
The best! I'll make you an elite miko.
キミにだけ キミが乳酸菌なんて! にゃっほろーわーるど!
Just for you, because you're lactic acid bacteria! Nya-hello World!
最高! エリート巫女に仕上げてあげるだにぇ!
The best! I'll make you an elite miko, nye!
配信中 今日は集まれ!
Streaming now, everyone gather today!
明日を燃やせ 笑顔でつかみに行こう
Burn tomorrow, let's go grab it with a smile.
想い出詰まったロケットは水がなくたって飛べるから!
A rocket filled with memories can fly even without water!
光ってほら! 虹色だにぇ!
Shine, look! It's rainbow-colored, nye!
一人ずつ名前呼ぶよ
I'll call out your names one by one.
ワン・ツー・さん・し
One, two, three, four
足りないもの探して
Searching for what's missing
お姫様見ていた
I was looking at a princess
あーゆーれでぃ 至ってはちゃめちゃ めっちゃ風なLady
Are you ready? Completely chaotic, a very windy Lady
そのままでいいじゃん
You're fine just as you are
壊してサヨナラ 下向きな精神 (マインド)
Break it and say goodbye, downcast spirit (Mind)
ベイビーダンス
Baby Dance
ねぇもう やだやだ
Hey, enough already
ミスってらんない
Can't keep messing up
踊ってベイビーダンス
Dance, baby dance
あたしはまだ諦めない
I'm not giving up yet
でも でも 全然だめかも
But, but, it might be no good at all
だってベイビーダンス うまくできないの
Because baby dance, I can't do it well
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられないな
Because baby dance, I can't convey it
もっと可愛くなりたいのに どうしたらいいかわかんないし
I want to be cuter, but I don't know what to do
まだ まだ いけるかな
Can I... still go on?
まだ まだ 言えるかな
Can I... still say it?
まだ まだ できるかな
Can I... still do it?
まだ... まだ...
Still... still...
ポンコツでドジでダメで 足りないとこばっかだって
Clumsy, scatterbrained, and no good, just full of flaws
きっとやめないんだ
But I won't stop
見ていてほしい
I want you to watch me
乙女のススメ!
Otome no Susume!
前向きぐんぐん 出発進行!
Looking forward, full speed ahead!
立ち止まる予定あるわけない
I have no plans to stop
笑顔にさせちゃう 神様信仰
I'll make you smile, faith in God
それつまり どこのどちら様?
In other words, who and where are you from?
さあ始めようか 空を染め上げて
Now, shall we begin? Dyeing the sky
あっちもこっちもそっちもどっちも 日っちもさっちも 華やかに変えてゆこうよ
Here, there, and everywhere, let's change it all elegantly
さくらひらり 時は来たり 天つ乙女のように きっと
Sakura fluttering, the time has come, like a heavenly maiden, surely
きらきらり輝くから 信じてついてきてね
Because it will shine brightly, please believe and follow me
さくらひらり 夢を見たり どんな困難だってきっと
Sakura fluttering, dreaming dreams, no matter how difficult it is, surely
キミと二人 乗り越えるよ うまずたゆまず さあ進め!
We'll overcome it together, you and I, steadily, let's go!
はーい! みんなにゃっほろー!
Hi! Nya-hello everyone!
エリート巫女アイドル、さくらみこです!
I'm the elite miko idol, Sakura Miko!
さくらみこ生誕祭2025 "Remember colors" に来てくれてどうもありがとう!
Thank you so much for coming to Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2025 "Remember colors"!
はい、さくらみこ生誕祭！
Yes, Sakura Miko Birthday Festival!
こちらですね！
This is it!
スクショ感想をたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you post lots of screenshots and thoughts!
はあ〜！やっとということでね！
Phew! Well then,
1曲目はさくらみこオリジナル曲メドレーでした！
the first song was Sakura Miko Original Song Medley!
ソロライブではね、歌えなかったオリジナル曲も入れてみたくて、
I wanted to include original songs I couldn't sing at my solo live...
メドレーやっちゃおうかなって軽い気持ちでやったらね、
...so I thought, "Maybe I'll do a medley," without thinking much...
大変なことになりました！
...but then it turned out to be quite a challenge!
はい！どうでしたかみんな？よかったかな？
Yes! How was it, everyone? Was it good?
アルバムもね、たくさんみんな聞いてくださいね！
Please listen to the album a lot too!
今回のコンセプトは、見ての通り、
The concept this time is, as you can see,
お姫様！お姫様となっております！
...a princess! A princess concept!
そして、去年のソロライブの感謝も込めたライブとなっております！
And this live is also filled with gratitude for last year's solo live!
みんなたくさん本当にいつもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much as always!
うわあああ！
Uwaaa!
見てください！衣装！
Please look! My outfit!
ソロライブでお披露目したドレス、見て！
Look at this dress I first showed at my solo live!
かわいい！
It's cute!
靴もね、あの靴、靴見える...あ、
And the shoes too... the shoes... look... oh,
靴もね、こちらガラスの靴になってるんだよ！
the shoes are glass slippers!
シンデレラですね！
Like Cinderella.
そしてあの、色もね、本当はですね、
And the color too... actually,
ソロライブではピンクのね、ドレスをたくさん着てたんですが、
at the solo live, I wore many pink dresses,
今回は白のドレスでやっていこうと思います！
but this time, I decided to go with a white dress!
かわいい？かわいい？えへへ。
Cute? Cute? Hehe.
はあ〜！
Phew!
あ、このステージだ！ステージもね、
Oh, this stage! The stage too,
さくらのお姫様のコンセプトで作ってもらいました！
was made with the concept of Princess Sakura!
すごい！うわ！
Amazing! Wow!
すごい！カメラ見えてる！
Amazing! Look at the camera!
いや素敵ですね。豪華になりましたね。
It's wonderful, isn't it? It's become so luxurious.
この後もいろんなね、演出があるかもなのでお楽しみに！
There might be various effects coming up, so look forward to it.
そして、最後には告知もありますので、
And finally, I have announcements,
最後まで絶対見てね！
so make sure to watch until the end!
それでは、ゲストパートいくぞー！
Well then, let's go to the guest part!
シンデレラ
Cinderella
作詞・作曲: DECO*27
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
だっだっだっうぉー 大丈夫ばなし
Daddada-o, a "it's fine" story
ちょっとサナギになって出直すわ
I'll become a chrysalis and start over
愛とか恋とか全部くだらない
Love and all that, it's all pointless
がっかりするだけ ダメを知るだけ
Just brings disappointment, just learning what's wrong
あたし馬鹿ね ダサい逆境じゃん
I'm a fool, aren't I? This is a lame adversity
ホントのところは あなたにモテたい
The truth is, I want you to like me
失敗するのにビビってるだけ
I'm just scared of failing
加工なしの厳しめの条件じゃん
The conditions are strict, with no filters
ちょっとこんな時 どんな顔すればいいか
Hey, in times like this, what kind of face
教えてほしい
should I make? Please tell me
まあちょっと「愛してる」だとか
Well, with words like "I love you"
そんな言葉で壊れてみたい
I want to try being broken by such words
じれったいな ハロー残念なあたし
It's frustrating, hello to the disappointing me
困っちゃって イヤイヤ
I'm in trouble, no no
じれったいな 決まんないの前髪が
It's frustrating, I can't get my bangs right
怒っちゃって イライラ
I'm getting angry, so irritated
だっだっだっうぉー 大好きは
Daddada-o, saying "I love you"
もっと可愛くなって言いたいのに
I want to say it when I'm cuter, but...
だっだっだっうぉー 大丈夫ばない
Daddada-o, it's not fine
ちょっとサナギになって出直すわ
I'll become a chrysalis and start over
あ…えと、いや、なんでもない
Ah... well, no, it's nothing
言いたいこと言えたことないや
I've never been able to say what I want to say
目と目と目 止められないの
Eyes and eyes and eyes, I can't stop them
逸らしちゃって待って 自己嫌悪
Turning away, wait, self-loathing
じれったいな ハロー残念なあたし
It's frustrating, hello to the disappointing me
困っちゃって イヤイヤ
I'm in trouble, no no
じれったいな 入んないのこの靴が
It's frustrating, these shoes won't fit
怒っちゃって イライラ
I'm getting angry, so irritated
鐘が鳴って 灰になって
The bell rings, turning to ash
あたしまだ帰りたくないや
I don't want to go home yet
バッて転校すへ 飛び込んでみたいから
Suddenly, I want to dive into the change
じれったいな ハロー残念なあたし
It's frustrating, hello to the disappointing me
困っちゃって イヤイヤ
I'm in trouble, no no
じれったいな 決まんないの前髪が
It's frustrating, I can't get my bangs right
怒っちゃってる
I'm getting angry
じれったいな 役前のシンデレラ
It's frustrating, the pre-role Cinderella
ビビっちゃって フラフラ
Getting scared and dizzy
ハローをくれたあなたと
With you, who gave me a hello,
踊っちゃって クラクラ
dancing and feeling dizzy
だっだっだっうぉー 大好きは
Daddada-o, saying "I love you"
もっと可愛くなって言いたいのに
I want to say it when I'm cuter, but...
だっだっだっうぉー 大大丈夫ばない
Daddada-o, it's not fine
お待ちになって 王子様
Please wait, Prince
だっだっだっだー ダメよ順序とか
Daddada-da, no, the order and stuff
もっと仲良くなって そうじゃないの？
We should get closer first, right?
だっだっだっだー マジで大丈夫...
Daddada-da, really, it's fine...
蛹になって
Become a chrysalis
出直すわ
And start over
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall
世界で一番可愛がるのはやめてや
Stop giving all your love to the prettiest one in the world
棘のような視線刺さる
Stinging gazes like thorns pierce through
優しいフリした彼女が
She, who pretended to be kind,
素敵な晩餐もてなした
Served a wonderful dinner
そっと口に含むと　笑み
As I gently take a bite, a smile
薄れゆく　ああ
Fades away, ah
意識の中で
Within my consciousness
夢を見る
I dream
いつかのおとぎ話
Of a fairy tale from long ago
時が止まる
Time stops
お願いKISSで目を醒まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if taking me out of this white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみは
The hatred that pierces me
ドラマ的な事情
Is just a dramatic circumstance
祈っても
Even if I pray,
君はまだ来ない
You still haven't come
ああ
Ah
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall
ネクタイ任せや頬に挨拶するから
I'll leave the tie to you and greet your cheek,
妬みをかわれてしまった
So I ended up being envied
七人の小人　色めく
The seven dwarves stir,
助ける素振り　知らんぷりね
Pretending to help while looking away
そっと首を掴まれ　笑み
As my neck is gently grabbed, a smile
一粒の　ああ
A single drop, ah
涙さえも
Even of tears
拭えなくて
I can't wipe away
呼吸もままならない
I can't even breathe properly
視界伏せた
My vision darkened
消えそうだから早く駆けて欲しいの
I feel like I'm disappearing, so please hurry to me
訳は聞かないで　応えられない
Don't ask why, I can't answer
望まない憎まれは
The unwanted hatred
深い愛の二乗
Is the square of deep love
もうすぐで
In just a moment,
いなくなるのかな
I'll be gone, I wonder?
ああ
Ah
途切れてく　ああ
It's breaking off, ah
命の音を
The sound of life
毒リンゴを
The poisoned apple
食した少女のように
Like the girl who ate it
眠りにつく
I fall into a sleep
お願いKISSで目を醒まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
胸の中の声　届きますか？
Can the voice in my chest reach you?
階段を上ったら
Once I go up the stairs,
ドアを開けるだけで
By just opening the door
見つかるよ
You'll find me
ああ
Ah
お願いKISSで目を醒まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if taking me out of this white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみは
The hatred that pierces me
ドラマ的な事情
Is just a dramatic circumstance
祈っても
Even if I pray,
君はまだ来ない
You still haven't come
ああ
Ah
消えてしまう
I'm disappearing
その前に...
Before that happens...
わがままプリンセス
Selfish Princess
一生私のそばにいてね
Stay by my side forever, okay?
誓いますか？ここにサインして！
Will you vow? Sign here!
忘れられない思い出を
Unforgettable memories
これから沢山作ろう
Let's make many from now on
イエイ！イエイ！イエイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
恥ずかしそうに聞いてくるけれど
You ask me bashfully
君の好きなところを脳内検索中
I'm searching my brain for what I like about you
感じたまま口に出せば
If I say what I feel out loud
照れ笑いしてとても愛すぎる
You'll smile shyly, it's just too lovely
ダイダイダイスキ！
I love you so, so, so much!
超キュートなワタシを見て？
Look at the super cute me?
目を離しちゃダメじゃん
You can't take your eyes off me
誰が一番カワイイかって？
Who's the cutest, you ask?
決まってるでしょ！
It's already decided!
常識！
Common sense!
今日からもっと素直になってスキを伝えて！
Be more honest from today and tell me you love me!
スキススキスキ
Love, love, love, love
キミのハートをゲッチュー
Get your heart
逃さないように確保！
Capture it so it doesn't escape!
いつでも独り占めできる
I can have you all to myself anytime
気分は最高
I feel great
なんでもわがまま聞いてくれる
You listen to all my selfish requests
キミに夢中
I'm crazy about you
I LOVE YOU
一生私のそばにいてね
Stay by my side forever, okay?
誓いますか？ここにサインして！
Will you vow? Sign here!
こんなにも可愛い私を
Me, who is this cute
一人にはしないでね
Don't leave me alone, okay?
喧嘩することもあるかも？
We might have fights sometimes?
それでも好きでいてくれるよね？絶対
But you'll still love me, right? Definitely
忘れられない思い出を
Unforgettable memories
これから沢山作ろう
Let's make many from now on
イエイ！イエイ！イエイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
特別な日に気分“超”ローテンション
On a special day, feeling "super" low tension
君は忘れてたよね
You forgot, didn't you?
間抜けな顔でごめんて
Saying sorry with a goofy face
言い訳なんか聞きたくない
I don't want to hear any excuses
勘弁してもう信じられないよ
Give me a break, I can't believe you anymore
ダイダイダイ嫌い！
I hate, hate, hate you!
何が悪いかわかってんの？
Do you know what's wrong?
ほら言ってみ？言えないじゃん！？
Come on, say it? You can't, can you!?
もうどうしていつもそうなの？
Why are you always like that?
1ミリたりとも誠意感じない
I don't feel a single millimeter of sincerity
最悪！
The worst!
不真面目トーク
Insincere talk
怒りはリンク
Anger is linked
お仕置きだよ
It's punishment time
ビシバシビシバシ
Bishibashi, bishibashi
次は無い、これが最後よ
There won't be a next time, this is the last
夢中になってくれなきゃ
If you don't become crazy about me
ダメよ！
No way!
嘘はない 真実(こたえ)はただひとつ
There's no lie, there's only one truth (answer)
私だけの...
My very own...
見つけちゃった
I found it
チュッ
(Kiss)
世界中どこ探しても
No matter where you search in the world
キミみたいに素敵な人はいない！
There's no one as wonderful as you!
イナイ！
None!
二人ならなんでもできる
Together we can do anything
LOVEパワー大爆発
LOVE power huge explosion
ドカン！
Boom!
毎日笑いあって生きよう
Let's live laughing with each other every day
たくさんの笑顔で朝から
With lots of smiles from the morning
超ハッピー
Super happy
特別な時間が待ってる
A special time is waiting
手を繋いでどこまでも
Holding hands forever
イエイ！繋いでどこまでもイエイ！
Yay! Holding hands forever, yay!
何度だってキミにスキを伝えよう
I'll tell you I love you over and over again
嫌いになんかならないでよね
Don't ever grow to hate me, okay?
最大級の愛を心から送ろう
I'll send my maximum love from the bottom of my heart
いつまでもずっと
Forever and ever
イエイ！
Yay!
一生私のそばにいてね
Stay by my side forever, okay?
誓いますか？ここにサインして！
Will you vow? Sign here!
こんなにも可愛い私を
Me, who is this cute
一人にはしないでね！
Don't leave me alone, okay!
せーの！
Ready, go!
I LOVE YOU
喧嘩することもあるかも？
We might have fights sometimes?
それでも好きでいてくれるよね？絶対
But you'll still love me, right? Definitely
忘れられない思い出を
Unforgettable memories
これから沢山作ろう
Let's make many from now on
イエイ！イエイ！イエイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
Wa-wa-wa-wa Yay-yay-yay-yay
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラと滾れ
Burn and surge
眠っているだけの正義
Justice that's just sleeping
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero
La la la...
かっこいい君には
For the cool you
僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
I wonder if I'm not reliable enough
そりゃそうだよなって
I guess that's true
今もこうして迷ってる
As I'm still lost like this
La la la...
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブアンドテイクさ
Give and take
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero
今なんじゃない？メラメラと滾れ
Isn't it now? Burn and surge
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice lurking even within me
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse
ほら
Look,
気付けば手を握っている
before I know it, I'm holding your hand.
いったいぜんたいそんなに荷物を
What on earth is that baggage
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
you're carrying? Where are you going?
ねえねえ待って
Hey, hey, wait!
僕にちょっと預けてみては
Why not try handing a bit of it to me?
信じてばかりの僕と
With me, who does nothing but believe,
信じることが怖い君と
and you, who are afraid of believing,
どちらが正しいのかなんて
who is really in the right?
誰にも分からないさ
No one can say for sure.
僕らだけの世界
It's a world just for us,
ギブとテイクさ
of give and take.
補い合えた暁には
At the dawn where we complete each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want to see the same dream as you.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて
Torturing yourself by trying to be 'cool',
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは少し
and the one who left you all alone...
僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
it's partially my fault, isn't it? I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But reality is what we must look at.
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now is the time for me to save you.
抱えないで 信じて
Don't bottle it up. Believe in me.
頼ってほしいんだ
I want you to lean on me.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる
Burning and seething within,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
there's a sense of justice lurking even in me.
どうしようもない
I'm driven by a
衝動に駆られて
helpless impulse.
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, before I know it, I'm holding your hand.
ほっておけない
I can't just leave you be.
そんなに荷物を
With all that baggage,
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
where are you going?
ほんのちょっと
Just a little bit...
僕にちょっと預けてみては
Why not try handing a bit of it to me?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I, too, want to be your hero.
できっこないを やらなくちゃ
I've gotta do the impossible.
どんなに打ちのめされたって
No matter how much you're beaten down,
悲しみに心をまかせちゃだめだよ
you must not give your heart over to sadness.
君は今逃げたいって言うけれど
You say you want to run away now,
それが本音なのかい？
but is that how you truly feel?
僕にはそうは思えないよ
I don't think so at all.
何も実らなかったなんて
Saying nothing ever came of it
悲しい言葉だよ
is such a sad thing to say.
心を少しでも不安にさせちゃだめさ
Don't let your heart be filled with even a bit of anxiety.
灯をともそう
Let's light the way.
あきらめないでどんな時も
Don't give up, no matter what.
君なら出来るんだどんなことも
You can do it, you can do anything.
今世界にひとつだけの
Just now, I saw a
強い力を見たよ
powerful strength unique in this world.
君なら出来ない事だって
Even the things you think you can't do,
出来るんだ本当さ嘘じゃないよ
you can do them. It's true, I'm not lying.
今世界にひとつだけの
Just now, I saw a
強い光を見たよ
powerful light unique in this world.
I wanna be a 君のすべて
I wanna be... everything to you.
今年もみこの誕生日祝ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for celebrating Miko's birthday again this year!
最高の...
The best...
...夢をみんなと叶えていくから！
...dreams, I'll make them come true with everyone!
ずっと、ついてきてね！
Keep following me, forever!
やはり自分じゃだめだなんて 無駄な言葉だよ
Saying you're not good enough is just a waste of words
心を少しでも 不安にさせちゃだめさ
Don't let your heart feel even a bit of anxiety
灯りをともそう
Let's light the way
あきらめないで どんな時も 君なら出来るんだ どんな事も
Don't give up, no matter when, you can do it, no matter what
今 世界にひとつだけの 強い光をみたよ
Right now, I see a strong light, the only one in the world
君ならできない事だって 出来るんだ ホントさ 嘘じゃないよ
The things you thought you couldn't do, you can do them, it's true, it's not a lie
今 世界にひとつだけの 強い光をみたよ
Right now, I see a strong light, the only one in the world
I wanna be your 君の全て
I wanna be your everything
ドキドキして Rouge?
My heart is pounding, Rouge?
いきますよ〜！
Here I go~!
ムザイン ムザイン 美少女ムザイン
Innocent, innocent, young girl innocent
マリン！ マリン！ マリンもムザイン
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent too
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, even more dizzy
美少女無罪♡パイレーツ
Young Girl Innocent♡Pirates
ねえ 言ったよね？ 年齢なんか関係ないってさ
Hey, you said it, didn't you? That age doesn't matter
そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
That you'd love me including all those troublesome things
ねえ 言ったよね？ 言ってない？
Hey, you said it, didn't you? You didn't?
ふーん、そういうこと言うんだ。 ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
Hmm, so that's what you're saying. By the way, 'young girl innocent' applies on this ship, you know?
まかせて！ 魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Rejuvenation with magic
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ
My secret real face is only for you
トクベツですよ〜？
It's special, okay~?
AH... アタシ厄介よ AH...
AH... I'm a handful, AH...
AH... 港なんかじゃ はしゃげないわ
AH... I can't just frolic at the harbor
近頃はね 宝の島に してほしい気分
Lately, I'm in the mood for you to make it a treasure island
出航ー！！
Set sail!!
キュートな正義 美少女無罪
Cute justice, young girl innocent
キミの一番目指して
Aiming to be your number one
ヨーソロー！
Aye-aye!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃう！ iAhoy!!
To be honest, I'm not confident, but I'll do my best! iAhoy!!
みゅるん まゅん
Myurun mayun
恋する気持ち17歳
Feeling in love like a 17-year-old
0時(テッペン)になっちゃうわ 大人の時間
It's becoming midnight, adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, even more dizzy
ドキドキして Rouge?
My heart is pounding, Rouge?
ああ、お許しくださ〜い！
Ah, please forgive me~!
このマリンの 魅力！ 魔力！ 不可抗力！
This Marine's charm! Magic power! Force majeure!
罪な女ね？
I'm a sinful woman, right?
離さないで つかまっていて
Don't let go, hold on tight
世界の広さ 見せてあげるから！ 出航ー！！
I'll show you how big the world is! Set sail!!
キュートな正義 美少女無罪
Cute justice, young girl innocent
キミの一番目指して
Aiming to be your number one
ヨーソロー！
Aye-aye!
冗談も大好きだぞ 真剣よ Ahoy!!
I love jokes too, but I'm serious, Ahoy!!
みゅるん まゅん
Myurun mayun
恋する気持ち17歳
Feeling in love like a 17-year-old
0時(テッペン)になっちゃうわ 大人の時間
It's becoming midnight, adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, even more dizzy
ドキドキして Rouge?
My heart is pounding, Rouge?
まだ早い♡
It's still too early♡
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
弱気で流したアングル
The angle where I looked weak
いつもドキドキだね第一声
The first words are always heart-pounding
にゃっはろー！！ ばっはろー！！
Nyahallo!! Bahallo!!
震えた声も ノートの文字も
The trembling voice, the writing in the notebook
みんなみんな手つないでGO
Everyone, everyone, hold hands and GO
(変わってるねって) そーなんだ (なんて言ったの？) まーいっか
(You're strange) I see (What did you say?) Oh well
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
The words I've been swallowing
君と笑った 恋でほら咲いて
Laughing with you, look, blooming with love
はんぶん！ こんな私でも もーはんぶん！
Half! Even someone like me, another half!
祈っててね 本当
Keep praying, seriously
元様？ どっち？ わかんない！
Master? Which one? I don't know!
本当は！ さくらんぼメッセージ
Actually! Sakuranbo Message
受け取って いせーのーせで！
Receive it, one-two-three!
きっともっとキュンしちゃうような
Surely, something that'll make your heart throb even more
さくらんぼメッセージ
Sakuranbo Message
つぼみに ギュッと 詰め込んで
Packed tightly into a bud
君の前では私
In front of you, I'm...
私らしくいていいよね？
Is it okay if I'm just myself?
誰かじゃなくて 君がいいよって
Not just anyone, I want you
絶対！ 何度でも言うよ
I'll say it again and again, definitely!
もう一回！
One more time!
好きだって本当？
You really love me?
元気ありそう？
Are you doing well?
どっち？わかんない
Which one? I don't know
本当だー！
It's true!
さくらんぼ メッセージ受け取って
Cherry, receive the message
いっせーのーせで！
On the count of three!
ぎゅっと キュンとしちゃうよな
Tight, it'll make your heart throb
さくらんぼ メッセージつぼみに
Cherry, into the message bud
ぎゅっと詰め込んで
Pack it in tight
君の前では私
In front of you, I'll...
...私らしくいていいよね
...be myself, okay?
好きでいていいよね
Is it okay if I keep loving you?
ねぇ 思い出したんだ
Hey, I remembered
そっと涙した日を
The days I quietly cried
さあ 数えてみようか
Come on, let's count them
これまで起こした奇跡は
The miracles we've created until now
ひとつ 止まらない足で
One, with feet that don't stop
ふたつ 超えていく夢も
Two, even dreams that we surpass
みっつ 繋がる絆は
Three, the bonds that connect us
君と広げてきたんだよ
I've expanded them with you
何度でも咲くように
So they bloom again and again
続いていくこの物語
This story continues
まだ見たことのない
Let's go find the scenery
景色を探しにいこう
that we haven't seen yet
花ひとつずつが
Each flower,
小さくても ほら
even if they're small, look
支え合えたら
if we support each other
桜になれるよ
we can become cherry blossoms
僕らが繋いだ
The big tree
大きな木は まだ
that we've connected
これからも
will continue to...
春風に乗って
...ride the spring breeze
伸びてくのさ
and grow
Wow...
甘く
Sweet
ほろ苦い夢
bittersweet dream
これでいいか これがいいか
Is this okay? This is better
折れかけたあの日
That day when I almost broke
ここに
Here,
間違いはなくて
there are no mistakes
正解もなくて 自分次第って
and no right answers; it's up to me
怖くて仕方ないけど
I can't help but be scared, but...
誰かじゃない 「君」と見たい
It's not just anyone, the scenery I want to see with "you"
景色は鮮明で...
...is vivid...
それじゃあ
Well then,
ここで
right here,
足踏みなんか
I can't just
していられないじゃん！
stand still, can I!
Oh Yeah! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah! Among the countless stars
Oh Yeah! 光は君がくれた
Oh Yeah! You gave me light
Yeah 超えていけるさ！
Yeah, we can overcome it!
Oh Yeah! SUPERNOVA 起こせ今！
Oh Yeah! Cause a SUPERNOVA now!
Oh Yeah! 何度だって翔べる
Oh Yeah! We can fly as many times as it takes
これは紛れもなく 僕らの軌跡
This is undeniably our trajectory
Hi friends!!
こんな現在を 愛せるように
So that I can love this present moment
君に向けて歌おう 心が叫んでる
I'll sing to you; my heart is screaming
Oh Yeah! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah! Among the countless stars
Oh Yeah! 光は君がくれた
Oh Yeah! You gave me light
Yeah 超えていけるさ！
Yeah, we can overcome it!
SUPERNOVA 起こせ今！
Cause a SUPERNOVA now!
Oh Yeah! 何度だって翔べる
Oh Yeah! We can fly as many times as it takes
これは紛れもなく 僕らの軌跡
This is undeniably our trajectory
普通も ”あたりまえ”もない
There's no normal or "taken for granted"
君が君らしく在れるように
So that you can be yourself
もっと！ ずっと！ 届けよう
More! Forever! Let's reach out
不思議と怖くはないんだ
Strangely, I'm not afraid
綺麗事 絵空事でもない
It's not a platitude or a pipe dream
さあ、行こう！
Come on, let's go!
この物語は終わらない！
This story will not end!
Wow...
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't ever stop being an idol
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もう ずっとずっとずっと
For a long, long, long time
ステージにいて
Stay on the stage
ねがもし君のところ 離れたなら
If I were to ever leave your side
君はちょっとさみしくなるかな
I wonder if you'd feel a little lonely
いじわる考える
I think such mean thoughts
好きな人がいるのなら 内緒にして ねえ
If you have someone you love, keep it a secret, okay?
神様は 将来と指輪を どこかに隠してね
God, please hide the future and the ring somewhere
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ 髪の色
I matched my hair color to your "likes"
私の中 君だけで
Inside of me, there's only you
過剰摂取は中毒ね
An overdose is an addiction
責任とってね 大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't ever stop being an idol
優しい目も 真面目な顔も 全て知ってる 私が言う
I know everything from your kind eyes to your serious face, so I'm saying this
絶対 空で輝いて ずっと
Definitely shine in the sky forever
星は街じゃ 輝かないの 眩しい君が世界一だよ
Stars don't shine in the city, you, the dazzling one, are number one in the world
好きだー！
I love you!
君の夢はなんですか？ 教えて欲しい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it
星のない空 それが当たり前で
A starless sky, that was normal
暗い道に 目が慣れずに 踏み出すのも怖かった
My eyes wouldn't get used to the dark path, and I was afraid to take a step forward
そんな時 やっと見えた光
At that time, I finally saw a light
絶対 君は歌ってて
Definitely keep singing
ただのわがままわかってても 君はキラキラ一生がいい
Even if I know it's just selfishness, I want you to sparkle for a lifetime
絶対 大きなステージで 一列目でも 前で感じたい
Definitely on a big stage, even in the first row, I want to feel you in front of me
今日の歌い方 なんか好きだなあ
I kind of like the way you're singing today
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つ この関係は
Your effort, my love, this relationship is built on that
強くて脆いの 星の幸せを願った
It's strong yet fragile, I prayed for the star's happiness
だけど…
But...
辞めて だって君はアイドルよ ずっと
Don't stop, because you are an idol, forever
初めて目が合った日から 今日も明日も君ばかりだ
From the day our eyes first met, today and tomorrow, it's only you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't ever stop being an idol
これは報われない おとぎ話 恋よりももっと好きだ
This is an unrequited fairy tale, I love you even more than a crush
魔法よどうか解けないままで
Magic, please stay unbroken
Lu lu lu...
まだまだ小さな 蕾だったあの頃
Back then, when I was still a small bud
冷たい風に 震えていたあの頃
Back then, when I was shivering in the cold wind
誰もが静かに 通り過ぎていく日々
Days when everyone passed by quietly
立ち止まってそっと 微笑んでくれた
You stopped and gave me a gentle smile
鏡を覗いたって 写真に収めたって
Even if I look in the mirror, even if I take a photo
ホントの色なんて ずっと わからないまま
I'll never know my true colors
遠くで咲き誇った キレイな花のように
Like a beautiful flower blooming in the distance
なりたくて なれなくて 春を待っていた
I wanted to become something but couldn't, so I waited for spring.
君の瞳の中
In your eyes,
反射した私を見て
look at me reflected there.
初めて自分の色を知れたんだ
For the first time, I was able to know my own color.
まだ満開じゃないけど
I'm not in full bloom yet,
鮮やかな夢を映し出せるよ
but I can project a vivid dream.
そこに君がいてくれたから
Because you were there for me.
La la la...
どれだけ自分を綺麗に描いても
No matter how beautifully I draw myself,
どれだけ自分を大きく描いても
no matter how grandly I draw myself,
君の目に映る 私はいつと同じように
the me reflected in your eyes is just the same as always,
不器用すぎて凸凹で 弱気なままで
being too clumsy, uneven, and remaining timid.
花が咲いた夢を見てた
I had a dream where the flowers bloomed,
きっといつか触れてみたいな
I want to try touching it someday.
花が咲いた夢を見てた
I had a dream where the flowers bloomed,
ずっとずっと春を待っていた
I've been waiting for spring for a long, long time.
曇り空の下 涙に遮られて
Under the cloudy sky, blocked by tears,
光が届かないときでも
even when the light doesn't reach,
昨日と変わらずに
without changing from yesterday,
明日に芽を伸ばしてゆこう
let's stretch our sprouts out towards tomorrow.
だって
Because
Reflection
そこに君がいてくれるから
it's because you are there for me.
君の瞳の中
In your eyes,
反射した私を見て
look at me reflected there.
初めて自分の色を知れたんだ
For the first time, I was able to know my own color.
まだ満開じゃないけど
I'm not in full bloom yet,
鮮やかな夢を映し出せるよ
but I can project a vivid dream.
この画面いっぱいに
All over this screen,
花びらの一つ一つを 好きになった
I've come to love every single petal.
そこに君が
Because you are there,
いつも君が
because you are always there.
いてくれたから
Because you were there for me.
Oh...
みんな、生誕ライブ見てくれてありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for watching my birthday live!
ここで告知が3つあります！
I have three announcements to make here!
1つ目はこちら！
The first one is this!
さくらみこ誕生日記念グッズが出ます！
Sakura Miko birthday commemorative goods are coming out!
キービジュアルはおるだん先生に描いていただきました！
The key visual was drawn by Orudan-sensei!
イラストのテーマは今回のライブのコンセプトと同じ、さくらのお姫様です！
The theme of the illustration is the same as the concept of this live, "Sakura Princess"!
フルセットはこんな感じになっています！
The full set looks something like this!
それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
さくらのお姫様LEDアートパネル。
Sakura Princess LED Art Panel.
背景を光らせることができるアートパネル。
It's an art panel where the background can be lit up.
...となっております。
...and it looks like this.
ドレスをまとってお姫様になった、あのライブでのみこを思い返せるグッズとなっております。
This merch will let you look back on Miko becoming a princess in that dress during the live.
思い返せるグッズとなっております。
It's a collection of goods to help you remember.
次はこちら！
Next up is this!
ちびみこ指パペット～巫女衣装＆35P着ぐるみver.～です！
Chibi Miko Finger Puppet: Miko Outfit & 35P Kigurumi ver.!
キーホルダーとしても使える指パペットが登場！
A finger puppet that can also be used as a keychain is here!
35Pの着ぐるみを付けたり外したりもできるので、気分に合わせてカスタマイズしてね。
You can put the 35P kigurumi on or take it off, so customize it to suit your mood.
次はこちら！
Next up is this!
さくらのお姫様 うたた寝ラバーマスコット。
Sakura no Ohime-sama: Napping Rubber Mascot.
つい、うたた寝しちゃったみこをマスコットとして再現しました。
We've recreated Miko who accidentally fell asleep as a mascot.
みんなのお家でみこがスヤスヤします。
Miko will be sleeping soundly at everyone's home.
ちっちゃいので可愛いよ。
It's small and cute.
最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
35Pふわふわカードホルダー。
35P Fluffy Card Holder.
35Pにカードホルダーになってもらいました。
I had 35P become a card holder.
みこのホロカを入れてもよし、
You can put Miko's Holoka in it,
特典のチェキ風ブロマイドカードを入れてもよしの汎用性の高いグッズです。
or the bonus Cheki-style bromide card. It's a very versatile item.
そしてそして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！チェキ風ブロマイドカード！
And then, here's the full set purchase bonus! A Cheki-style bromide card!
数量限定バージョンは、みこの直筆サインが入ります。
The limited quantity version will have Miko's handwritten signature.
通常バージョンにも箔押しのサインが入りますが、
The standard version also has a foil-stamped signature,
直筆が欲しい方は、早めにご購入ください。
but if you want a handwritten one, please buy it early.
22時10分から発売開始となります。よろしくお願いします。
Sales start at 10:10 PM. Thank you.
今回はフルセット購入特典もつきます。
This time, there's also a full set purchase bonus.
特典ボイス、タイトルは「みこのこれから」。
The bonus voice title is "Miko's Future."
ソロライブを終えたみこが、今後について35Pに話すような内容です。
It's Miko talking to 35P about her future after finishing her solo live.
ソロライブから今日の3Dライブの間のお話なので、
Since it's a story from between the solo live and today's 3D live,
このボイスを聞いた後にもう一回配信を見返すと、より心に染み渡るかも。
listening to this and watching the stream again might touch your heart even more.
さらに！フルセット特典として、去年の9月から発売された
Furthermore! As a full set bonus, from the card game released last September,
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚つきます。
you'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game.
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。
The card is only for those who purchase from the Hololive Official Shop.
特典につくのは推しアピールできる「推しホロメンカード」です。
The bonus is an "Oshi Holomen Card" to show off your favorite.
カードの詳細や遊び方については、ホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the homepage for card details and how to play.
カードは日本語版のみとなりますので、ご了承ください。
Please note that the card is only available in Japanese.
告知二つ目は、こちら！
The second announcement is this!
お待たせしました！さくらみこ 1st Live「Flower Fantasista」Blu-ray発売決定！やったー！
Sorry to keep you waiting! Sakura Miko 1st Live "Flower Fantasista" Blu-ray release confirmed! Yay!
超エリートに咲き誇った、みこの初めてのソロライブを何度でも見返せるので、
You can watch Miko's first solo live, which bloomed in super elite style, as many times as you want,
みんな、絶対に購入してください！
so everyone, please be sure to buy it!
詳細は後日発表されますので、お楽しみに。
Details will be announced later, so look forward to it.
告知の三つ目は、こちら！
The third announcement is this!
「Reflection」のMVが公開されます！
The MV for "Reflection" will be released!
この後すぐプレミア公開になりますので、お見逃しなく！
It will be a premiere right after this, so don't miss it!
そしてそして、まだあります。
And then, there's more.
鳴門鯛焼本舗とさくらみこ、コラボ第3弾が全国49店舗で開催中です！
The 3rd collab between Naruto Taiyaki Honpo and Sakura Miko is underway at 49 stores!
3月31日までなので、ぜひ、みんな食べに行ってください！
It's until March 31st, so everyone, please go and eat some!
そして、さくらみこSHARPコラボの「喋るエリート家電」が現在受注販売受付中です！
And the "Talking Elite Appliances" from the Sakura Miko x SHARP collab are now accepting pre-orders!
うるさいほどよく喋るので、みんなぜひ、お家に置いてね。
They talk a lot, almost to a noisy extent, so please bring one home.
詳しくは公式サイトを見てください。
Please check the official site for details.
そして、今週末はホロライブ6th fes.「Color Rise Harmony」とEXPOがあります。
And this weekend, we have Hololive 6th fes. "Color Rise Harmony" and EXPO.
みんな、応援よろしくお願いします。
Everyone, thank you for your support.
以上、お知らせでした。
That's all for the announcements.
それではですね、この後メンバー限定で撮影会とアンコールライブがあるので、
Now then, after this, we'll have a photo session and an encore live for members only,
みんな、さくら組に入ってね！
so everyone, please join the Sakura-gumi!
おつみこでした！バイバイ！
Otsu-miko! Bye-bye!
みこの色はみんながおしえてくれたんだよ。
Everyone taught me what Miko's colors are.
みんなと見た景色を何度だって思い出して
I'll remember the view I saw with everyone over and over again,
もっと光輝くステージへ！！
and head towards an even brighter stage!!
ありがとうだよー
Thank you so much!
みこの色はみんながおしえてくれたんだよ。
Everyone taught me what Miko's colors are.
みんなと見た景色を何度だって思い出して
I'll remember the scenery I saw with everyone over and over
もっと輝くステージへ…！！
and head to an even more shining stage...!!
ありがとうだよー
Thank you!